[Music]
Welcome to Business Central launch
edition of 2025 release wave 2. This
session is about how we have now
opensourced all the PowerBI apps for
Business Central. Getting started with
PowerBI can be a daunting task because
the data models for any system including
Business Central um is large and uh with
the open-source PowerBI apps we have for
Business Central, you don't have to
start from scratch. You can uh get high
uh high quality semantic models and high
quality designed reports out of the box
and you can use them as is. But if you
also want to do changes to to these
either models or reports, you can just
download the source code and take it
from there. In release wave 1, we open
sourced most of the apps. Remaining
three is coming now here in wave two,
which is uh sales, the apps for sales,
for purchasing and for projects. Um and
hopefully this can unlock a lot of um BI
projects at your uh company.
Yeah. So this is uh just a table if you
need to take a screenshot of that.
Everything is now uh available by the
time of this recording. Uh all the
source code uh you can download. So how
can you do that? Let's see that in
action.
So let's imagine that you want to modify
the sales app. Here uh I have it opened
in the PowerBI service. And um
the way to get to the PBX file, the code
for the report is simply to choose file
and then download this file. Now for the
apps that were released in 2025 release
wave 1, those have those apps have this
download menu or part of the menu
enabled. For sales, purchasing and for
projects, the download this file option
only will only be present in the new
versions we are publishing here in
October. But download this file. Just
download the PBX file and now you have
the source code.
So, if you want to learn more about the
PowerBI apps for Business Central, uh
there's a landing page called
aka.ms/bcanalytics,
that takes you to the first link up
here, the the overall landing page of
everything. You then need to navigate
two levels down. One is uh KPIs and then
there's a section here of PowerBI apps.
The PowerBI apps have a lot of different
uh articles both how to install them,
how to configure them, FAQ, a
troubleshooting guide and others. So go
check that out. Especially if you want
to start um make them their own um you
might want to see how they work. And
actually how they work is also
documented. So each of the PowerBI apps
have their own part of the documentation
where both the reports are documented as
well as the semantic model. So all the
measures in the semantic model are are
documented here in doc. So you can kind
of learn how they're calculated and then
you can go to the source code and see
the actual DAX expressions for it.
That's it. A few more links. If you are
not following on us on LinkedIn, the
product group, please go to aka.ms/bc
LinkedIn and follow us there. We will
now likely announce not unlikely, we all
announce on a weekly basis uh news and
things about the product. Uh so if you
want to be ahead of the game, follow us
there. You're watching this on YouTube.
We do have a YouTube channel for for the
product group as well, aka.ms/bc
YouTube. Do follow us there. You get not
only launch edition events uh videos
like the one you see here, but also
videos on co-pilot AI agents, tips and
tricks, technical deep dives, and even
what we call under the hood. under the
hood is kind of what's coming in the
next wave way and and these surface
typically way before you see them in the
release plan.
If you are a business central partner,
the aka.ms/bc
all link is the is the the landing page
for all the aka links that are relevant
for you. And if you are part Microsoft
partner for business central and not on
the yammer yet, please join us there on
aka.ms/bc
yammer. This is where all the
discussions questions uh around the
product happen. No customers are there
but a lot of your friends from the
partner channel is is there. So you're
missing out if you're not on Yammer. And
the third link I want to highlight is
the office hours. every month uh
typically every month we have an an
office hour session that's open both for
customers and partners um and these are
like sessions about the the things that
are related to the next versions on the
next areas in business central so the
aka link aka.ms/bc
office hours go check out the program
and hopefully join us for for an office
hour in the future with that thank you
so much I wish you a great day and I
hope you watch some of the other
sessions here in the business central
launch edition. Thank you.